All right, you can stay here with
Blackie. It won't be long.
Hey, Sarah, what you doing? I'm waiting
for Aunt Hattie. She's in the post
office.
Uh, Sarah, you wouldn't happen to know
what Aunt Hattie's planned for the big
mathematics test next week?
No, how would I? Well, she must keep a
copy of that at -earth cottage.
With the answers, maybe?
Felix King.
Do you think that I would stoop so low
as to go through Aunt Hattie's papers
just for a stupid test?
Well, I just thought... Besides, she
keeps it locked up in the schoolhouse.
If you would just study instead of
always trying to find an easy way out,
maybe... I don't.
I just... Felix, look.
What? No.
Stop that.
Hello, Uncle Alan. Sharon.
I think I'd better be going. I'll see
you later.
Alex King!
Morning, Abner.
The man I want to see.
Huh? I'm going to have a word.
Are you still looking to buy a horse?
Well, I've been thinking about it.
Because if you are, I heard of one for
at the racetrack over Somerset.
Oh? You have to see it today, though.
I understand.
Pat Shores leaves for Halifax right
soon.
And he has to sell.
From what I hear, it's a deal of a
lifetime.
Well, I could hardly take Felix to the
track janitor have my hide Alec King
delivery another day like this. Well,
thanks for the tip after Come
on Felix, we got one more stop me
is like how majestic Murphy is some
horse.
What are you going to do with all that
money you want?
Wait till Mother finds out.
Uh, it might be best if you didn't
mention anything about this to your
We'll just keep it a secret between us.
What?
Oh, you can count on me.
Besides, I didn't come here expressly to
bet.
No, no, of course not.
I didn't. It was a horse I heard about I
wanted to have a look at. Of course.
Don't see you at the track very often?
Oh, just looking around.
This little Felix?
Sure is.
Never too young to learn the horses, eh,
Alec? Yeah.
Thank you.
Did you see all that money?
Boy, I'll bet there was more than you
won.
We gonna bet again, Father?
No, I think we should quit while we're
ahead, don't you?
I wouldn't be selling them, but I need
the cash. I'm moving to Halifax, and I
can't afford to take him with me.
He's a pretty hefty size, huh?
Oh, he's a big one, all right. But, you
know, he was quite a racer in his day.
You'll get your money's worth out of
Caesar there.
What do you think, Felix?
I guess he's okay.
That means we'll take him, Mr. Shaw.
Well, I'm glad to know that he'll have a
good home.
Uh -huh.
See, I'm too late.
Ain't so, Hank.
I was thinking of expanding a bit, you
know?
Two wagons, two drivers.
I hear your business is thriving.
Can't complain.
I'm delivering clear across the island
now. But, uh, first come, first served.
You got yourself a real deal, Alec.
Pat, I'll see you later.
We've got Blackie.
Well, Felix, Blackie's getting on, you
know. He is not.
He's the smartest horse in the lot. He
knows every word you say.
Smart or not, I'm thinking of selling
him. Sell him?
Sell Blackie?
You see, he heard you.
What do you even think of such a thing?
He's part of the family. Blackie's going
to run forever.
Exactly, Felix. He's getting old.
Soon he's going to be too old to be of
any use at all.
It's fine, isn't it? Would you tell me
if I couldn't do my work around the
If that was the case, we'd have sold you
years ago.
Please, Mom, this isn't funny. We have
to keep him.
Let me have him, then.
I'll take care of him.
Oh, you will?
How are you going to pay for his keep,
then?
I don't know. I just will. You can hire
us. We do work for you.
Felix, I'm not paying you to do your
chores.
Maybe someone else will hire us to do
theirs.
Aunt Hetty or... Hetty, come on, Felix.
Home chores done. Never mind handle a
job.
It'll only be part -time.
I know I can do it. It keeps blocking
feed.
Oh, please.
I don't want you to tell them.
Well, I don't know.
They're always telling me I should take
on more responsibility.
All right.
But only... Thank you, Father. Thank
you. Now, you listen to me. This is on a
trial basis.
It mustn't interfere with either your
schoolwork or your chores.
I won't let you down, Father.
Blackie won't either.
Mother, guess what?
I'm going to start a delivery service
with Blackie. Oh, that's nice, dear.
Really, Dan, it'll be easier to dress a
slipper eel.
It's going to be my responsibility.
I'm going to earn money to keep him.
I'll take Blackie from a buggy father.
Don't worry. I'll make sure he's safe in
the barn. Fine, son.
Felix, a delivery service? Alec, he's
only a boy.
How can he handle something like that
all by himself?
I'll help him get started. It'll be good
for him. A little responsibility.
Oh, and I bought another horse today.
Good deal.
Horse? A horse?
You boys grow up so fast.
Felix King, it's about time you showed
up.
Felix, here. This is your job. You
finish it.
Felix, do you hear me?
I'm sick and tired of doing your chores
as well as mine.
Where have you been all day?
What are you doing?
Certainly do with a fresh coat of paint.
But it's perfect.
Perfect for what?
My delivery service.
Your what?
Well, if you want to fix it up, you're
welcome to it.
Thank you.
I can't wait to start.
Here.
But only after I finish my chores, of
course.
Of course.
Thanks, Sarah.
Did the lettering better than I would
have.
Here, Blackie.
I made this especially for you.
No, Blackie.
It's much too cold for that baby out
here.
That horse will eat almost anything.
Just like you, Felix.
You two make the perfect couple.
You're just jealous, Felicity, because
Blackie and I are going into business.
Felix King, quit dreaming.
You've never once in your life finished
anything that you've started, and I
doubt that this newest whim will prove
any different.
I'm going to make you eat your words,
Felicity.
This is going to be the best delivery
service in the whole county.
I'll believe that when I see it.
You'll see it, Felicity.
You'll see it. Come on, Blackie.
You were so right, Alec.
And I think it's wonderful that you
encouraged him.
I've never seen Felix so enthusiastic.
About working, that is.
Well, I have to admit, it was a clever
way to steer him in the right direction.
You're a simply wonderful father.
I can hardly share in this nauseating
display of parental narcissism. I do
concede. It's about time Felix learned
to show his thumb responsibility.
So what if he fails?
It'll be a good experience for him to
have to answer to someone else.
Hide this family for a change. Felix
won't fail. Anything that boy sets his
to is bound to succeed.
Felix, dear, I'd like you to know that,
um, I'll be your first customer.
I'm extracting a basket of pears to
arrive at the general store tomorrow,
I'd like the Felix King delivery service
to pick them up for me.
For the going rate?
For the going rate.
Have you got anything that needs
delivering, Aunt Hetty?
Oh, well, uh...
A few nights generally I like to look
over purchases myself.
Oh, come on, Aunt Hattie.
But yes, you could pick up some jars of
preserves at Farmer Steele's tomorrow
morning.
Flacky, finish my hat.
Whoa, whoa, easy.
Calm down.
What kind of horse is that, Alec?
Looks like it's never been hitched to a
buggy in its life.
Well, not recently, but I'm getting him
used to it slowly. He'll calm down soon.
Well, you get what you pay for.
Easy, easy, easy.
As my father always used to say.
Whoa, easy, fella. Digger, keep quiet.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, Caesar. That's enough
for one day. Come on.
Come on.
I'll take care of you, Blackie.
You'll never have to leave King Farm.
No more ultra pasture for you.
Still got a lot of good ears left. Yes,
sir.
Hold still.
There's a good boy.
Bet you haven't had a brushing like this
for years.
Here.
Got a reward for you.
What an adorable cart.
Now, I think we'll have lots of odd
delivery jobs for you, Felix.
I mean, it makes good business sense for
the store to offer such a service, and,
well, we'd gladly pay for it.
Oh, uh, you know, no, no, no, no, no.
I think we've paid for part of it
already.
No, now, come on. There you go. Say
hello to your mother for me, okay? No
That's it.
Oh.
No
Every
careful
with
business. Can't complain.
Hard work, huh?
I hope this teaches you nothing comes
easy in this world, put it there.
Remember, you only reap what you sow.
You know what, Aunt Hetty?
I couldn't agree with you more.
And you know how you're always teaching
us to do things by whole, not by half?
There's going to be nothing halfway
about this business.
That's good to hear.
There you are, my boy.
Cash on the barrel, as they say.
Thank you, ma 'am.
Aunt Hedy will do nicely. Thank you,
Felix.
Oh, gracious providence, Felix King.
What's happened to my preserves?
I wouldn't buy preserves for Mr. Steele
anymore if I were you.
I knew I couldn't trust a man the minute
I laid eyes on him.
The vicious dog has something to hide.
Well, it's never happened before.
that horse.
Blackie, no.
Blackie. Blackie, no.
My flowers.
He's hungry.
I promised him something to eat when we
got home. I see.
How's he feel about preserves?
Well, that wasn't so bad for the first
day, now was it, Blackie?
Hope everyone doesn't have a vicious
dog, though.
25, 50, 75, 85, 90, a dollar.
A whole dollar.
I might even have enough to buy Blackie
some oats.
For a treat.
Is that your list for tomorrow, Felix?
Yep, I'm going to be busy.
You should advertise, Felix. My father
always said that advertising was crucial
to the growth of any business.
Where are you going to feed the
chickens, Felix?
Where do you have to finish counting
this money again?
Well, make sure you do. You know our
bargain.
I know, I know.
Oh, Felicity, look at these.
I'll have to cut away half of them.
Oh, we must have a talk with Mrs.
Lofton. These aren't up to her usual
standards.
Yuck, they look like they've been chewed
already.
Look at all these bruises.
I wonder what could have happened to
them.
I just want
to welcome you to the business community
of Avonlea, son.
Don't we, boys?
Bravo! Sure, sure.
So you got yourself a little delivery
business, huh?
Yes, sir.
You got to watch yourself there, Hank.
He might give you a run for your money.
Well, I enjoy a little competition.
May the best man win, right, Felix?
Right, Mr. Webster.
Now, listen, why don't you... Why don't
you call me Hank?
I mean, after all, you're one of us now.
Right, Mr... Hank.
I'm pulling in my horns.
I planted half the potatoes that I
planted last year.
Well, that's a fool thing to do.
A business has to expand to stay healthy
in these times. I've hired another
driver. The only way to expand any
business is to advertise.
My card?
Tuck it up where you can see it.
Afternoon, gentlemen.
Well,
good for him.
this meeting.
Oh, I'm sorry, dear, but I'm just...
Would you kindly knock before entering
the future?
Felix King, you watch the way you speak
to me. I'm your mother. I shouldn't have
to knock just to put laundry in your
bedroom.
This is an office by day.
As I was saying, based on the success of
my first week in business, I've decided
to take on some partners.
It's my belief in these economic times.
Business has to expand in order to be
healthy.
What do you mean, Felix?
The only thing expanding around here is
Felix's head.
Don't you know how to knock?
Don't get fooled into working for him,
Cecily.
You're just in a knot, Felicity,
because, you know, I wouldn't give you
chance to be in my business even if you
paid me. I wouldn't give you two cents
for your so -called business, Felix.
Just get out!
Gladly.
what I meant about expanding my
business?
Well, it's really very simple, Sarah.
If I have more people working for me, I
can make more deliveries. I make more
deliveries, I make more money.
So would you care to join me in my
business?
What would our return be?
A small share of the profit.
An equal share of the profit split three
ways.
What? I'm the one who started this
business.
You can't have an equal share.
Felix, it will give us more incentive.
That's what my father always said.
Well, we'll do it on a trial basis.
Agreed? Agreed.
Agreed. Partners. And Digger, too.
Here you go.
Don't you want it?
There you go, Daniel.
get you hitched up for delivery, too.
And company.
That's better.
No, Digger.
Digger, hold still.
There's the good dog. Don't you look
handsome?
You're gonna be rich.
Like you know.
There, there, Caesar. That's better.
Cecily, you keep Digger away.
Finally got him hitched up.
Yes, I did.
He'll never be a match for Blackie.
Well, we'll see.
Dinner's ready!
Felix, you chase after him.
You go after him! Me?
Hey, there comes that.
Oh, hey.
That horse took off like a race horse.
Well, no wonder. You ring that bell.
What's a bell got to do with it?
Nothing.
Nothing. Peter!
Good morning, Mrs.
Wilkes. Right on time.
Here's your first customer, Sarah.
Mrs. Wilkes needs this parcel delivered
this afternoon.
Well, that's what we're here for, Mrs.
Wilkes.
Isn't it wonderful to see children being
so industrious?
Well, thank you very much for letting us
set up here, Mrs. Lawson. Now, Mrs.
Wilkes, I'll just need a little bit of
information.
Ow! Ow!
What is going on?
All right, $1, $1 .05, $1 .10, $1 .15,
$1 .35.
Where's our share? Shh, I'm going to
lose count.
$1 .40,
$1 .50. Part of that is ours.
Put it back, Sarah.
I can't give you your share until I
figure out how much it costs to eat
blackened food.
Oh, great, now I lost count.
That's not fair.
$1, $1 .05.
Felix, come on. Children, stop it right
now.
I told you so, Cecily.
Felix, could you possibly do that
someplace else? I'd like to set the
dinner. I've already lost count once.
Felix, do what your mother tells you.
For someone who can count money so
quickly, I find it hard to believe that
practically failed that mathematics test
we had at school today.
Felix King, now you promised that you
wouldn't sacrifice your schoolwork for
sake of that business.
Or your chores.
I had to feed the chickens today because
someone forgot to do it again.
All right, all right.
it will hardly matter that I made a few
mistakes on a mathematics test.
Or I forgot to feed the chickens all
day.
Aunt Abigail's trying out on the three o
'clock train.
Mr. Gillis at the sawmill. This is hot.
Sarah, I'd like a few words with you.
I'm sorry, I can't, Aunt Hattie. I have
to copy these out. I'll need your help
polishing the silver. I'm having a few
of the ladies over, and... Sarah,
there's constant confusion. Will you
stay in one spot while I talk to you?
I don't think they see these orders.
Sarah?
So, Felix, first do the order at the
lumber mill, then do Mrs. Potts' order
the general store. She's apparently too
sick to pick it up.
Then to the train station, Fran,
Abigail, and Cecily.
You have three pickups at the general
store, including at Hedy's Groceries. I
can't do all that.
Sarah, there's way too many orders for
me. You'll have to do some.
I can't. I'm too busy.
Do you have any idea how hard it is
sitting at a desk all day taking orders?
I mean, you're lucky. You got to be
outside.
Uh, Cecily?
If I have to put up with you three
swarming around like bees, the least I
expect is for my groceries to be
delivered first.
Now make sure you're back with them by
four o 'clock.
The ladies from the Improvement Society
are coming for supper, and I have a stew
to make.
Phillips King, have you any idea how
many germs lie festering within a
mouth?
Next thing you know, you'll be getting
lockjaw.
I hope he does.
Sarah, I'll need your help to set the
table.
I can't, Aunt... Hattie, I have to go
back to the general store. Sarah, I'll
drop her off then, Hattie.
Whoa, Blackie, whoa.
Here you are, Mr. Gillister.
Good. Good man. I've been waiting for
this.
Thank you.
Eddie will be mad if you...
have any business lined up for the next
few days.
Why? We don't have any orders, Felix,
because all I've heard all day are
complaints. Even in my own household.
Aunt Hattie was furious. Her groceries
ended up in the pond.
The pond?
How could you do such a stupid thing?
It wasn't my fault.
Digger isn't used to being hooked up to
a stupid cart.
You should have been in charge of that
stupid dog.
Digger's not stupid.
Well, somebody is.
You are so smart yourself, Felix King.
You're the one who got all Mrs. Lawson's
deliveries mixed up.
Well, if you had the delivery straight
in the first place, this wouldn't have
happened.
I guess this is what I get for letting
you two be part of my business.
Is that so?
What a mean thing to say, Felix.
We quit. Right, Cecily? Right.
So does Digger.
Having trouble, Mr. Big Businessman?
It's that mutiny I smell in the air.
Felicity, be quiet.
You shouldn't blame Sarah and Cecily for
your lack of business.
Would you just get out, Felicity?
Oh, dear, Felix. I think it's time you
listened to your older sister before you
really get hurt.
You thought you were such a big shot.
Didn't you realize that your only
customers were your relatives and
And couldn't you see that they were only
doing it to humor you?
Not true.
Oh, yes, it is.
They were all laughing behind your back.
Everyone but you knows that.
How many times did you think you could
deliver damaged goods?
If you were a real delivery company, you
wouldn't have lasted a day.
All right, we're coming.
Eddie, what brings you here?
What's this?
A bill.
One hat.
Eight jars of preserves and four bags of
groceries. They ended up at the bottom
of the pond, and I ended up serving
leftovers to the ladies of the
Society. Well, I wasn't going to say
anything, but I have a set -up and a
all evening, listening to Sarah's tale
of woe, and I'll not let it pass without
saying something.
What are you talking about?
Your son, Alec King, that's what. Oh,
this delivery business has gotten right
out of hand.
I don't know what kind of father you are
not to have noticed.
I am certainly relieved that Sarah no
longer has anything to do with it.
What are you talking about, Hetty?
I'd like to be reimbursed. Oh, Hetty,
you're making such a fuss over nothing.
Adults should stay out of children's
affairs. It's far better they straighten
out their own problems themselves.
Oh, they can straighten out their own
problems as much as they like. But when
comes to my problems, I expect a little
adult intervention.
Oh, Janet.
I know that this is beyond your
experience, but I think you should
boys have to learn to do things the hard
way before they learn to do things the
right way.
That's what Father always said.
Like most things Father said regarding
children, God rest his soul.
It's a load of hooey.
Too much.
Lockie?
Felix? I want a word with you.
This delivery business of yours has
gotten out of hand.
At least a little blabbermouth.
Cecily hasn't said a word.
Nobody thinks I can do anything around
here.
They're all just waiting for me to mess
up.
Now, look, son, we had an agreement, and
so far you haven't kept up your end of
it. You're not getting your schoolwork
done.
I'm doing most of your chores, and Hedy
just came by with a bill for damaged
goods a mile long.
I'll pay it. With what?
Besides, I thought this was about
blackie, not money.
It is.
No, you're not doing this for Blackie
anymore. You're doing this for Felix.
Well, it's finished. This is it.
What do you mean?
You're out of business.
As of now.
And if there's any more talk like that,
Blackie will have to go.
Let him say what he wants, Blackie.
You and I are a team.
We'll show.
We'll show them all.
Felix, hurry up. You're going to be late
for school.
I'll catch up with you in a minute.
Here, Archie Gillis is the proud owner
of some pretty fancy undergarments.
Is that right, Felix?
I'm not going to give anything to be
there.
And here, advertising ain't always a
ticket to expanding your business.
Oh, heck no, it expanded my business.
Ever since Felix started advertising,
I've never been busier.
Pay no attention to these guys, Felix.
It's better to go bankrupt with your age
than mine. I mean, your father can
always help you out. I'm not bankrupt.
I'm not bankrupt.
Felix's delivery is still in very
healthy shape.
Yeah, well, your horse looks like he's
on his last legs.
Blackie?
Blackie is the best and smartest horse
that ever lived.
You just tell him where we're going and
he goes.
Hey, hey, Felix.
Hey, hey, Felix. Hey, come here, son.
Come here. Come on. Listen, come here.
Now, we're just giving you the...
Son, huh?
No hard feelings?
All right, now listen, I got a little
proposition for you. I got a contract to
move some bags of sand from the train
station to Markdale later today.
Now, how about if I take half the load
and you take the other half, and we'll
see who gets to Markdale first.
And the winner gets to take the entire
fee.
How about that?
Great. All right, you're on.
Okay.
Here we go.
There you go.
Abner, where's Felix?
He's racing Hank to Markdale on a bet.
He accepted a bet? When did he leave?
He'll be halfway there now. About half
an hour ago.
If you ever take a few minutes.
And I suppose it never occurred to
anyone to try and stop Felix. He's a
And Blackie's too old to be racing.
Well, we're way ahead of that handgun
shit by now, eh, Blackie? We'll show
We'll show everyone.
They won't dare laugh at us again.
Calm down. I've got to help him!
No!
No! No, help him! Help, Blackie! No!
We've got to get him out!
Calm down.
Calm down. I will.
I will.
Felix Black, he's... He didn't make it.
He didn't make it. He's gone.
I made your favorite, strawberry
rhubarb.
No, thanks.
I've got chores to do.
Felix can't wait to do his chores.
Something's up.
Here.
I fed them.
Boy, were those chickens glad to see me.
I guess they were pretty hungry.
Mind you, they're lying a lot. I
collected three dozen eggs. Can you
that? Three dozen.
I think it's some kind of record.
Can I give you a hand?
Oh, no, thank you.
Just cleaning up. I'm fine.
Well.
Really?
You know, my father...
He believed that boys had to learn
things the hard way before they learned
right way.
But I don't think that anyone can learn
the right way unless they have some
guidance.
And I should have given you more help.
So we both made some mistakes.
It's all right, really.
You sure I can't give you a hand?
No, just finishing up.
Stuff you just said?
Wasn't your fault.
I was responsible.
I took the bet.
Wish you just would have sold them.
You'd still be alive.
Oh, God.
I shouldn't have made you think that
I...
Tell Blackie if the business failed, if
I'd realized how much he meant to you,
I'd never have sold him.
And I'm sorry I made you feel you had to
prove yourself.
But there are some things in life, son,
that you just have to put behind you.
I know.
I will, but I love Blackie.
And I'll never forget him ever.
You go on. I'll be out in a minute.
So beautiful.
Is Felix around, Mrs. King? He's in the
barn, Mr. Webster.
I just want you to know I feel real bad
about what happened. It was a fool thing
to have done. Yes, it was.
But don't apologize to me.
I'd like to talk to the boy, Alec.
Oh, he's still pretty upset, Hank.
Oh, hello, Felix.
Mr. Webster.
I just want you to know I feel real bad
about what happened to your horse.
I just want to make it up to you
somehow.
His mother was a racehorse just like
Caesar.
Felix, come and see. A racehorse?
Caesar's a racehorse.
Look how strong he is. He's the
prettiest horse in Avonlea.
Good boy.
You're a hungry boy, aren't you, Star?
Star? I can't comb it. If you name like
Star, your name should be Majestic
Majesty.
Or Prince.